

# Ruslan Abuzant

MT4 Expert & IT Executive Manager

- +357 (95) 164-614
- /ruslanabuzant
- www.abuzant.com
- ruslan.abuzant@gmail.com

## WHY ME

A Visionary extroverted professional offering over 10 years' experience, 6 of them as a Senior IT Executive in the **financial services** industry, emphasis on improving efficiency, productivity, organizational consistency and contributed to firm growth by implementing business strategies using strong decision making abilities, solid analytical and problem-solving skills where I have gained thorough vast understanding of business models needs and the firm's core competencies. A values-based leader, a reliable partner and a fast learning business entrepreneur.

## **LANGUAGES**

Arabic
English
Russian
Hebrew

### **EXPERIENCE**

# METATRADER PLATFORM ADMINISTRATOR / OPERATION MANAGER SCOPEMARKETS LIMITED

Limassol, Cyprus

Sep. 2017 - Present

- Administration & Support of MT4/MT5/Ghost trading platforms.
- Manage all MetaTrader platform components of both MetaTrader4 and Metatrader5 including data-centers, history servers, feeds, ..
- Preparation, development and continuous optimization of disaster recovery plans
- Integration of various plugins for the Metatrader platform including integration of MAM, PrimeXM XCore and other complex plugins.
- Integration of third-party CRM and Affiliate systems for calculation of leads, profits, funnels and generated trading commissions.
- Database replication management of MT4 reporting server and integration of DB's into various CMS systems.
- Integrating newrelic and other server monitoring solutions to ensure zero downtime of trading server components.

### SENIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER & PRODUCT OWNER

AAATRADE LIMITED

Limassol, Cyprus

Feb. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- **Scrum** management for an **online trading platform** project. Architecture & implementation of frameworks and **API endpoints**.
- Development of a stand-along affiliate management system based and backed up by **MT4 Manager's API** with automated payments.
- QA of existing websites and web resources and migration from native PHP to Codelgniter3 and Laravel5, from Apache to Nginx.
- Provide **consultation** and intraday management for a mid-sized team of web developers, designers and solution integration team.
- Migration of internal mail system to use the MailGenesis
- Created a web reporting GUI using Codelgniter3 and UIKit2 for backoffice and compliance departments to manage account verifications and client segmentation based on pre-set filters.
- Built a web-based mathematical custom-indicator calculation engine with Javascript to be used as a backend API for web-based online trading platforms.

## **SKILLS**

- (W/L)AMP Server Setup, Support, Development & Administration
- Web Development (XHTML, HTML5, JS & jQuery, Ajax, XML, CSS2/3, SQL, PHP4/5, Codelgniter, Laravel, API's, WebSocket)
- Facebook/Google/Amazon Cloud API's, Google Adsense, Adwords, Analytics, Application Suite, Office Tool, Platform API's & SDK's
- httpd, SMTP, IMAP, DKIM, SQL, Squid, IPTables & DNS setup, maintenance & network administration
- Content Origin Routing , GeoIP CDN datacenter infrastructuring & setup.
- Database structuring & normalization (MyISAM/InnoDB)
- Extensive knowledge of all major CMS, CRM, e-commerce & social networking platforms. (SaaS/PaaS)
- SEO & SEM (blackhat, whitehat), PPC, Link Building & Optimization
- Payment systems & Merchant gateway integrations, crypto currencies, credit cards.
- Social marketing branding, analysis, audience segmentation & campaigning.
- Amazon AWS Cloud Platform & Development Tools

## **EDUCATION**

**B.Sc. Computer Information Systems**Odessa State Academy of Refrigeration
Odessa, UA (2005) GPA: 4.56

### Specialty:

Network Structure & Security (+2 yr.)

## CBDM & MT4 BACKEND DEVELOPER

SAB FINANCIALS LIMITED

Limassol, Cyprus

Jul. 2016 - Jan. 2017

- Setup of brand new MT4 trading network in **Equinix datacenters** over encrypted VPN tunnels. Reduced SYN/ACK time to <1ms.
- Integration of Tier-1/Tier-2 bank bridges into MT4 network for instant order execution based on Risk Management ACL's and policies. Developed a WebSocket app to aggregate prices from all involved parties to offer best bid/ask prices saving huge amounts of client's equity lost in fluctuating spreads.
- Implemented TeamWox/JIRA CRM's into corporate solutions package. and Integrated Zopim/Zendesk customer support suite reducing support tickets waiting interval to less than 4 hours.
- Development and implementation of a web based application to monitor server status across multiple datacenters and worked on load-balancing associated traffic based on originating countries and requested resource's availability among different servers.
- Worked closely with the CEO as a CBDM to strategically build global & regional partnerships. Negotiated deals and helped implementing global bridging and price aggregation solutions from PrimeXM

### WEB DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

SPLASH TECHNOLOGIES

Ramallah, Palestine

Jul. 2014 - Jun. 2016

- Introduced a business plan for a national & governmental powered content-filtering system to be applied as an additional security layer by all ISP and offered to end users as an add-on service for their ADSL/xDSL plans.
- Administered a sophisticated data mining phase aiming to build complex algorithms able to detect adware, malware, phishing, pornographic and terrorism related content.
- Integrated custom Google analytics and Tags as tools to identify different user segments and implemented a secure delivery system for related system notifications to maintain high SLA's.
- Administered the development of data encryption routines to ensure all user's traffic and filtered data is never visible nor accessible to third parties while still being accessible by the system itself to build more advanced algorithms in the future.

## **CERTIFICATION**

### **HEAD OF IT & DEVELOPMENT TEAM**

SWISS ALLIED BROKERS (DMCC)

Cairo, Egypt Aug. 2012 - May. 2014

2000 Master Computer PC Essentials

2000 Internet Explorer Administ

2000 Internet Explorer Administrator

2000 Written Russian

2000 MS Outlook Express

2000 Certified Computer Professional

2000 Microsoft Office User Specialist 1999 IBM Certified Specialist (RS/6000)

1999 Microsoft Certified System Engineer

1999 Microsoft Certified System Enginee 1999 Microsoft Certified Professional

1998 Microsoft Certified Technology

Specialist (MCTS)

By: Brainbench / 293290

1998 CySEC Basic Certification

By: Cyprus Securities and Exchange Commission

- Distribution of corporate servers over co-located datacenters and implementing adequate **firewall access policies**/monitoring
- Setup of multilingual call center and e-ticketing support system with complete integration into MetaTrader4 Server.
- Implementation of algorithmic trading capabilities with SQL-based risk management and analytics system.
- Built an online cabinet (dashboard) for traders, affiliates and introducing brokers with online trading capabilities and automated deposit, withdrawal and internal account transfer facilities.
- Used MT4 API to build custom Microsoft Windows applications for monitoring overall exposure of online trades with SMS notifications and integration with windows DDE for price monitoring.
- Implemented a DDoS mitigation system by moving all accessible resources behind CloudFlare protected IP's and added replaced all SSL on all servers with TLS for better security.

## REFERENCES

#### Mr. Gaies Chreis

coo

Metaquotes Software Corporation

T: +357-96-039-903 E: bin.esmtp@gmail.com

### **Mohammad Al-Touri**

Affiliate Sales Manager FX Clearing House (FXCC)

T: Upon Request

E: m.altouri@gmail.com

#### Tareq Abukhadijeh

Change Management Officer Information Management & Mine Action Programme (iMMAP)

T: +962 79 996 6432 E: tareq.z85@gmail.com

#### SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER

TUNEFOREX INVESTMENTS LIMITED

Limassol, Cyprus Dec. 2008 - Jul. 2012

### **NETWORK SECURITY OFFICER**

LITEFOREX (EX. MAYZUS INVESTMENTS)

Limassol, Cyprus Aug. 2007 - Oct. 2008

### **Web Developer**

Allied Brokers S.A.R.L

Amman, Jordan Apr. 2006 - Jul. 2007

## **NOTES**

Nationality: EU / Romanian Residency: Limassol, Cyprus

**EU Permit**: Yes **Smoker**: Yes